(鸟鸣声)
(BIRD SCREECHES)
(群鸟啁啾)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(蜜蜂嗡嗡)
(BEE BUZZING)
(远处鸟鸣)
(BIRD SONG IN DISTANCE)
(欢快音乐)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(汽车喇叭声)
(HORNS HONKING)
(门轴吱呀)
(DOOR CREAKS)
(音乐继续)
(UPBEAT MUSIC CONTINUES)
嗨！
Hey!
你单身吗？
Are you single?
我是Adore婚恋公司的红娘。
I'm a matchmaker at Adore.
想认识新朋友的话随时给我打电话。
Please give me a call if
you want to meet somebody.
我们有很多优质人选推荐给你。
We have a lot of great matches for you.
再联系
Talk soon.
詹姆斯你好
James, hi.
谢谢回电
Thanks for calling me back.
我想了解一下
你和我客户苏菲的初次约会。
Um, I just wanted to get some
feedback on your first date
感觉如何
with my client Sophie.
其实我现在正要去见她...
I'm actually on my way
to meet her right now...
不过今早我们简单聊过...
but I had a quick chat
with her this morning...
总体反馈很好
and the headline is, she had a great time
她希望能再见你
and would love to see you again.
喂？詹姆斯？
Hello? James?
詹姆斯：我想退出你们的服务。
JAMES: Yeah, I'd like to be
taken off the service.
能问问原因吗？
May I ask why?
詹姆斯：你们承诺介绍的是。
JAMES: I thought you were
going to set me up
优质女性
with high-quality women.
我说过要30多岁
身材匀称笑容甜美的。
I said: a fit woman in her 30s
with a nice smile.
她40岁还胖
She's 40 and fat.
- 她39岁- 39就是40岁。
- She's 39.
- 39 is not 30s, that's 40.
这种女人我根本不会右滑。
I would never swipe right
on a woman like that.
- 很遗憾你这么想- (挂断音)。
- I'm sorry you feel that way.
- (LINE DISCONNECTS)
(忙音)
(LINE BEEPS)
苏菲：我太开心了。
SOPHIE: I'm so happy.
(轻笑)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
露西你太棒了
You did it, Lucy.
当你说他47岁
年薪才15万的时候...
When you said that he's 47
and only makes 150K a year...
我差点拒绝 还好相信了你。
I almost said no, but I'm
really happy I trusted you.
虽然才第一次约会。
I know it's only been one date
我知道不该期望太高...
and I need to manage my expectations...
但这绝对是我经历过
最棒的初次约会！
but this is probably the best
first date I've ever had!
呃 苏菲 我刚和他通过电话。
Uh, Sophie, so I just got off
the phone with him.
他很享受和你的约会。
And he loved meeting you,
玩得很开心...
he had a great time...
但他觉得目前
But he doesn't feel like the chemistry
两人之间缺少火花。
is there for him at this time.
所以
So.
继续寻找吧
Onward and upward.
他不想第二次约会？
He doesn't want a second date?
是的
No.
他都秃顶了。
（轻声笑）
He's balding. (CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
他哪来的胆子？
How fucking dare he?
露西：约会就是场冒险。
LUCY: Dating is a risk.
你敢于冒险，这很勇敢。
You took a risk. It's brave.
苏菲：为什么给我介绍这种人？
SOPHIE: Why did you set me up
with someone like that?
他符合我们列出的很多条件...
He checked a lot of our boxes...
你也符合他的很多要求。
and you checked a lot of his.
所以，继续向前看吧。
So, onwards and upwards.
来聊聊你的下一个相亲对象。
Let's talk about your next match.
有个超棒的男士介绍给你。
I have an amazing guy for you.
他叫马克，是位医生，
His name is Mark, he's a doctor,
长得非常英俊...
he's very handsome...
头发浓密，48岁。
he has a full head of hair, he's 48.
苏菲：都快50了。
SOPHIE: That's almost 50.
以48岁来说状态很好。
He looks great for 48.
身材保持得不错，看着像40岁。
He's very fit. He looks like he's 40.
- 多高？
- 1米8。
- How tall?
- 5'11".。
是真有1米8还是虚报成1米8的
实际1米75？
Is he actually 5'11" or is he
actually 5'9" and is lying?
差个几厘米有什么关系？
What's a couple of inches?
苏菲：我不想浪费时间。
SOPHIE: I don't want to waste my time.
我没指望出现奇迹。
I am not asking for a miracle.
只求最基本的条件。
I'm just asking for the bare minimum.
我已经在降低标准了。
I'm trying to settle.
露西：苏菲。
LUCY: Sophie.
我理解你现在的心情。
I know how it feels right now.
但我向你保证...
But I promise you...
你会嫁给此生挚爱。
you're going to marry
the love of your life.
苏菲：我不信。
SOPHIE: I don't believe you.
没关系。
That's okay.
我相信。
I believe it.
（远处汽车鸣笛声）
(HORNS HONKING IN DISTANCE)
（模糊的交谈声）
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
（众人欢呼）
(ALL CHEERING)
今晚的主角来了！
Girl of the hour!
今晚我们齐聚在此。
Tonight, we're all gathered
为最优秀的红娘露西庆祝。
to celebrate the most talented Lucy.
这位眼光毒辣的婚恋专家...
One hell of a matchmaker
with razor-sharp instincts...
凭着敏锐的直觉——就在本周末，
and an eagle eye for chemistry
because this weekend...
她的客户夏洛特·B要结婚了！
her client Charlotte B.
is getting married!
（众人欢呼）
(ALL CHEERING)
夏洛特·B将嫁给彼得·C，
Charlotte B. is marrying Peter C.
这位白马王子
The Prince Charming
正是露西20个月前为她牵线的。
Lucy matched her with 20 months ago.
露西你现在促成多少对婚姻了？
How many marriages are you
responsible for now, Lucy?
九对。
Nine.
（齐呼）露西！露西！露西！
(CHANTING) Lucy! Lucy! Lucy!
露西，说两句！
Lucy, do a speech!
（齐呼）致辞！致辞！致辞！致辞！
(CHANTING) Speech! Speech! Speech! Speech!
好吧。
Okay.
我要说的是...
My speech is...
如果女方要求
that if the girl asks for
找个一米八的高个子...
a 6-foot-tall drink of water...
四十多岁年薪超50万美金。
in his 40s with a salary over 500 grand
还要...发际线完美...
and a... good hairline...
(众人哄笑)
(ALL LAUGHING)
你就得满足
you deliver.
(众人欢呼)
(ALL CHEERING)
今天和索菲·L谈得怎么样？
How did it go with Sophie L. today?
会籍团队花了一小时才说服她续约。
It took our membership team
an hour to get her to renew.
没救了
Hopeless.
恐怕整个纽约都找不到。
I'm afraid there's not
a single man in New York City
愿意和她约会的男人。
that'll date this girl.
问题出在哪里？
What seems to be the issue?
问题就在她太普通了。
That's the thing. There is
nothing wrong with her.
长相还行...
She's okay attractive...
收入还行，学历还行，性格还行。
okay money, okay educated,
okay personality.
就是没有突出亮点。
There's just not a standout quality.
她在主流婚恋市场缺乏竞争力...
She's not competitive
in the mainstream market...
又找不到细分市场。
and there is no niche market for her.
没错
Exactly.
如果没有独特卖点...
And if there's no specialty appeal...
在任何市场都找不到定位。
then there's no place
for her in any market.
确实棘手
That is tough.
可她是我现在最爱的客户。
And she's my favorite client right now.
虽然和其他人一样挑剔。
I mean, she's entitled like everyone,
但她很贴心...
but she's sweet...
而且现实理智，不疯癫。
and she's realistic, she's not crazy.
是个好姑娘
She's a nice girl.
总该有个男人
There's got to be a guy out there
就想找个好姑娘吧。
who just wants a nice girl.
马克·P怎么样？
What about Mark P.?
普普通通
He's okay.
露西：已经给她推荐过了。
LUCY: I pitched him to her already.
她怀疑他身高不到1米8。
She's afraid he's not actually 5'11".
我说现在能不能别纠结。
And I'm like, can we please not worry
这几厘米的差距？
about a couple inches right now?
毕竟你快孤独终老了。
Because you're about to die alone.
(轻笑)
(CHUCKLES)
知道吗 这个可以做手术。
You know there's a surgery for that.
治孤独终老？
For dying alone?
是增高手术
For getting taller.
最多能长15厘米。
Up to six inches.
把腿骨打断...
You break your legs, and...
拉伸后让骨头自然愈合。
extend it, let the bone heal itself.
这能改变人生
That's a game changer.
费用要20万美金。
It costs like 200K.
15厘米能让男人身价翻倍。
Six inches can double
a man's value in the market.
如果负担得起
If you can afford it,
绝对值得投资
it's definitely worth the investment.
那句话怎么说来着？
What's the saying?
"你不是丑，只是没钱罢了。"。
"You're not ugly,
you just don't have money."
露西：没错。
LUCY: Right.
(模糊的交谈声)。
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
你选好婚礼穿的裙子了吗？
Do you have a dress
picked out for the wedding?
选好了。
Yes.
你一个人去吗？
Are you going alone?
嗯哼。
Mm-hmm.
露西·M：永远的单身女王。
Lucy M.: The Eternal Bachelorette.
自愿独身主义者。
A voluntary celibate.
要我帮你介绍对象吗？
Do you want me to set you up with someone?
不用，我打算孤独终老。
No, I'm gonna die alone.
或者找个有钱老公。
Or get a rich husband.
反正都一样。
Same thing.
(露西轻笑)
(LUCY CHUCKLES)
(模糊的对话声)。
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
哈里：嗨，查尔斯。
HARRY: Hi, Charles.
见到你真高兴。(亲吻)。
Good to see you. (KISSES)
你真美。
You look beautiful.
天啊，看它们长得多大了。
Oh, my God, look how big they are.
妈。
Mom.
恭喜你们。
Congratulations.
很高兴见到你。
Nice to see you.
你真漂亮。
You look beautiful.
很高兴再次见到你。
Nice to see you again.
嗨，亨利。你好。
Hi, Henry. Hi.
帕特丽夏：我一直跟大家说。
PATRICIA: I have been saying to everyone
彼得和夏尔是我的理想伴侣...
that Peter and Char are my couple goals...
我也要找到属于自己的彼得。
and I need to find my own Peter
这事得怪你？
and you're responsible?
是我撮合了夏洛特和彼得，明白吗？
Well, I'm how Charlotte
and Peter met, okay?
但建立牢固的感情...
But it's up to the client
最终走向婚姻，
to build a strong enough relationship...
这取决于客户自己。
that leads to marriage.
但你怎么知道
But how did you know that
彼得就是夏尔的真命天子？
Peter would be the perfect guy for Char?
海梅：她不能说，这是行业机密。
JAIME: Well, she can't tell,
it's her industry secret.
(轻声笑)哪有什么行业机密。
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
There are no industry secrets.
我们随时都可能在现实生活中。
We can always meet our life partner
或交友软件上遇见终身伴侣。
out in the wild or swiping on apps.
但第一次约会最美好的结局...
But the happy ending to a first date...
不是第二次约会。
is not the second date.
是互相换尿布，
It's changing each other's diapers
最后为对方送终。
and burying each other.
你要找的是养老院的室友，
You're looking for a nursing home partner
和墓园里的邻居。
and a grave buddy.
选择什么样的伴侣...
Who our partner is...
决定了我们整个人生...
it determines our whole life...
和生活方式。
and how we live.
不是一年两年，
甚至十年，而是...
Not for one, two, ten years, but...
永远。
forever.
天啊。（轻笑）
Oh, my God. (CHUCKLES)
我太需要你了。
I need you so badly.
是的，我快绝望了。
Yeah, I'm desperate.
能给你我的名片吗？
Can I give you my card?
当然可以。
Of course.
我正在办离婚手续，等结束后...
I'm going through a divorce,
but once it's over...
我真的很想给你打电话。
I would really, really like
to give you a call.
听到这个消息我很难过。
I'm so sorry to hear that.
露西，她需要你。
Lucy. She needs you.
借过一下。
Excuse me.
(脚步声整齐响起)。
(FOOTSTEPS THUMPING IN UNISON)
我只需要和她单独待五分钟。
I just need five minutes alone with her.
(关门声)
(DOOR CLOSES)
- 嗨，夏洛特。
- 嘿，露西。
- Hi, Charlotte.
- Hey, Lucy.
露西：你还好吗？
LUCY: How're you holding up?
不太好。（轻声苦笑）
Not good. (CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
发生什么事了？
What's going on?
(夏洛特抽泣)
(CHARLOTTE SNIFFLES)
事情是这样的...
What's going on...
我是个现代女性。
is that I am a modern woman.
我本可以成为任何人，
Like, I could've been anything.
任何角色。
Anything.
但我选择成为...
But I chose to become...
一个新娘。
a bride.
这是我自己的选择。
I chose this.
又不是说我要结婚。
It's not like I'm getting married
是为了建立两个王国之间的...
because I need to forge a...
政治联姻。
relationship between two kingdoms.
也不是我家需要一头奶牛。（笑）
It's not like my family
needs a cow. (LAUGHS)
这是我自己的选择。
我选择嫁给一个男人。
I chose this. I chose to marry a man.
露西：夏洛特。
LUCY: Charlotte.
婚姻就是一场交易。
Marriage is a business deal.
从古至今
And it always has been
自从有人类婚姻开始就是如此。
since the very first time
two people did it.
如果交易不划算，你随时可以退出。
You can always walk away
if the deal isn't good.
作为介绍你和彼得认识的人，
And as the person
who introduced you to Peter,
我现在就可以陪你离开这里。
I will walk right out of here with you.
告诉我：你今天真的想结婚吗？
So tell me: do you not want
to get married today?
我必须结。
I have to.
- 露西：为什么？
- 因...（嗤笑）
- LUCY: Why?
- Bec... (SCOFFS)
我父母为这场婚礼花了很多钱。
My parents spent
so much money on this wedding.
我们花了数十万美元...
We spent hundreds
of thousands of dollars...
办这场婚礼，就为了。
on this wedding just so that
让我感觉自己像个该死的女人。
I could feel like a fucking woman.
露西：在你内心最阴暗、
LUCY: Why do you really,
最丑陋的角落里，
in the darkest, ugliest part of yourself,
你到底为什么想嫁给彼得？
want to marry Peter?
(夏洛特长叹)
(CHARLOTTE SIGHS)
我向你保证...
And I promise you...
我听过所有理由
I have heard every reason
一个人为什么要和别人结婚。
why a person wants
to get married to someone.
这些理由对我来说都不算惊人、错误或疯狂。
And none of them are shocking
or wrong or crazy to me.
这将是你我之间的秘密。
It will be a secret between you and me.
你保证会保密吗？
You promise it'll be a secret?
露西：我保证。
LUCY: I promise.
你不能告诉任何人。
You cannot tell anyone.
谁都不能说。这事太糟糕了。
Not a soul. It is so awful.
露西：我会带进坟墓里。
LUCY: I will take it to my grave.
他让我姐姐嫉妒。
He makes my sister jealous.
她虽然没明说，但我知道这是事实。
She's never said that,
but I know it's true.
她觉得他比她丈夫强。
She thinks he's better than her husband.
她觉得他...
She thinks he's...
工作更好，长得更帅。
got a better job,
that he's better-looking.
个子更高。
Taller.
而且...
And...
这让我感觉...
that makes me feel...
(抽泣)
(SNIFFLES)
...像是我赢了。
...like I've won.
(啜泣)
(SOBBING)
所以这是关于价值感的问题。
So this is about value.
彼得让你觉得自己很有价值。
Peter makes you feel valuable.
(轻笑)
(CHUCKLES)
是的，确实如此。
Yeah, he does.
他真的做到了。
He really does.
这会让你想嫁给他吗？
Does that make you want to marry him?
(轻笑)
(CHUCKLES)
(轻笑，抽泣)
(CHUCKLES, SNIFFLES)
(掌声)
(APPLAUSE)
(众人欢呼鼓掌)。
(ALL CHEERING, APPLAUDING)
(嘈杂的交谈声)。
(OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
嘿。
Hey.
我是哈里。
I'm Harry.
露西。
Lucy.
你是那个媒人。
You're the matchmaker.
你是新郎的弟弟。
You're the brother.
你来单身人士桌干什么？
What are you doing at the singles table?
我母亲希望我结婚。
My mother wants me to marry.
我可以帮你这个忙。
I can help you with that.
我刚才看到你在招揽客户。
I saw you recruiting earlier.
这样的婚礼简直是金矿。
A wedding like this must be a gold mine.
对我们公司来说这里机会很多。
There's a lot of opportunity
here for our company.
你的推销话术很完美。
Your sales pitch is perfect
因为你让人感觉这是他们自己的想法。
because you make it feel
like it's their idea.
你不是在告诉人们他们需要你，
It's not like you're telling
people they need you,
没人愿意听这种话。
nobody wants to hear that.
如果他们需要你，
If they need you,
那就说明他们有问题。
then something is wrong with them.
相反...
Instead...
你会说："你完全可以靠自己解决。
you're saying: "You could
do this on your own
"但如果你足够幸运能负担得起我的服务。
"but if you're lucky enough
to be able to afford me,
"为什么不呢？"。
"why not?"
你就是奢侈品。
You're a luxury good.
这样他们才会觉得离不开你...
Then they really do
feel like they need you...
就像离不开生活中其他奢侈品一样。
just like they need every
other luxury in their lives.
一旦你体验过400美元的发型设计。
Once you get your first $400 haircut,
就再也回不去廉价理发店了，对吧？
you can't go back to Supercuts, can you?
很简单。
It's easy.
不，你只是太优秀了。
No. You're just really good.
那是什么感觉？
What's it like?
什么什么感觉？
What's what like?
当红娘的感觉。
Being a matchmaker.
就像在停尸房工作。
It's like working at the morgue,
或者保险公司上班。
or an insurance company.
(轻笑) 怎么说？
(CHUCKLES) In what way?
1米88，1米68。瘦的，健壮的，胖的。
6'2", 5'6". Skinny, fit, fat.
白人，黑人，亚裔。
White, Black, Asian.
- 医生、律师、银行家。
- (轻笑)
- Doctor, lawyer, banker.
- (CHUCKLES)
10万，20万，30万。
100 grand, 200 grand, 300 grand.
吸烟，不吸烟。
Smoker, non-smoker.
但你一定很懂爱情。
But you must know a lot about love.
我只懂约会。
I know about dating.
有什么区别？
What's the difference?
约会需要付出很多努力。
Dating takes a lot of effort.
要经历无数试错。
A lot of trial and error.
承担大量风险和痛苦。
A ton of risk and pain.
爱情很简单。
Love is easy.
是吗？
Is it?
我觉得这是世界上最难的事。
I find it to be the most
difficult thing in the world.
那是因为我们无法控制它。
That's because we can't help it.
有时候它就突然闯进我们的生活。
It just walks into our lives sometimes.
你是在撩我吗？
Are you hitting on me?
- 绝对不是。
- (轻笑)
- Definitely not.
- (CHUCKLES)
但我确实认为
But I do think that you would be
你会是我们很多客户的理想对象。
a great match for a lot of our clients.
纽约需要更多直男。
We need more straight men
in New York City.
你看起来大概1米83。年薪多少？
You look about six feet tall.
How much money do you make?
就这么直接问？
Just straight up like that?
税前年薪8万美元。
I make 80 grand a year before taxes.
你赚得比这个多还是少？
Do you make more or less than that?
多。
More.
我就知道。
I know.
金融行业对吧？
Finance, right?
私募股权。
Private equity.
要喝点什么吗？
Do you want a drink?
- 好啊。
- 想喝什么？
- Sure.
- What do you want?
- 可乐加啤酒。
- (脚步声接近)。
- Coke and beer.
- (FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(闷响)
(THUDS)
嘿，老兄。
Hey, buddy.
嗨，约翰。
Hi, John.
现在在忙，晚餐服务结束后聊？
Working now, obviously,
but talk after dinner service?
嗯。
Yeah.
好吧。
Okay.
哈里的父亲：爱是最后的信仰...
HARRY'S FATHER:
Love is the last religion...
最后的归宿，最后存续的信念。
the last country,
the last surviving ideology.
除此之外还有什么值得相信？
So what else really
is there to believe in?
当你迷失方向时...
When you get lost...
我知道你有时会迷失...
and I know you'll be lost at times...
这就是人生。
it's life.
当你迷路时...
When you're lost...
答案很简单。
the answer is simple.
只需追随爱的方向。
Just go where love is.
(掌声)
(APPLAUSE)
众人齐唱：♪ 手牵着手 ♪。
ALL: ♪ Touching hands ♪
♪ 心连着心 ♪
♪ Reaching out ♪
♪ 感受彼此的温度 ♪
♪ Touching me, touching you ♪
♪ 甜蜜卡罗琳 ♪
♪ Sweet Caroline ♪
♪ 吧，吧，吧 ♪
♪ Bah, bah, bah ♪
♪ 美好时光从未如此美妙 ♪
♪ Good times never seemed so good ♪
♪ 太美妙！太美妙！太美妙！ ♪
♪ So good! So good! So good! ♪
(远处传来喇叭声与警笛声)。
(HORNS, SIRENS IN DISTANCE)
嗨。
Hi.
嘿。
Hey.
那么，是什么让他们如此般配？
So, what made them perfect for each other?
露西：相似的经济背景。
LUCY: Similar economic background.
政治立场一致。
Politically aligned.
外貌吸引力相当。
Well-matched in their attractiveness.
相似的成长环境。
Similar upbringing.
相似的成长环境？
Similar upbringing?
他们都来自幸福大家庭。
They both come from big happy families.
(嗤笑)
(SCOFFS)
"幸福大家庭"
"Big happy families."
没错。
Yes.
眼见为实。
I'll believe it when I see it.
只要相信"幸福大家庭"这个概念...
The perception of a "big happy family"...
就能拥有一个"幸福大家庭"。
is all you need to have
a "big happy family."
这就是灵魂伴侣的全部条件？
That's all it takes to be soulmates?
基本上是的。
Basically.
穷困潦倒...
Poor...
支持伯尼的...
voted for Bernie...
糟糕的原生家庭。
shitty family.
我们是灵魂伴侣吗？
Are we soulmates?
大概是吧。
Probably.
演艺事业进展如何？
How's acting going?
你看我像进展顺利的样子吗？
How does it look like it's going?
抱歉。
Sorry.
别道歉，是我太刻薄了。
No, don't be, I'm just being a dick.
我刁难你是因为感到难堪。
I'm giving you a hard time
because I'm embarrassed.
露西：你有什么好难堪的？
LUCY: What are you embarrassed about?
因为有份正经工作？
Having a job?
我在演话剧。
I'm in a play.
- 是吗？
- 是啊。
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
离演出还有段时间。
It's not for a while.
现在接这种零工就是想攒点钱...
I'm just doing jobs like this
to try and save some cash...
等排练开始就没空了。
before rehearsal starts.
真没想到今晚会遇见你。
Definitely didn't expect
to run into you tonight.
我想你了。
I missed you.
约翰：嗯。
JOHN: Yeah.
你连我长什么样都忘了。
You don't even remember my face.
露西：明白了。
LUCY: Got it.
(轻笑) 该你了。
(CHUCKLES) Your turn.
你现在有对象吗？
You seeing anyone?
你看见我坐单身桌了。
You saw me at the singles table.
(车辆驶过声)
(VEHICLE PASSING BY)
我也想你。
I missed you too.
(叹息)
(SIGHS)
等我忙完送你回家吧？
Can I give you a ride home
after I'm done finishing up?
我车就在这儿。
I have my car here.
好啊。
Yeah.
我们该叙叙旧。
We should catch up.
(播放舒缓的嘟喔普音乐)。
(SLOW DOO-WOP MUSIC PLAYING)
妈咪，妈咪。
Mommy, mommy.
要给我留电话？
Giving me your number?
招聘。
Recruitment.
对你哥哥管用，
Worked for your brother,
我觉得对你也会有效。
so I think it will work for you.
陪我跳舞就给你打电话。
I'll call you if you dance with me.
我会打给你的。
I'm going to call you.
但不是为了雇你。
But not to hire you.
我可能不是理想的约会对象。
I'm probably not someone you want to date.
为什么？
Why not?
因为下次恋爱我就要结婚。
Because the next person
I date, I'm gonna marry.
那么红娘想嫁
So what kind of a person
什么样的人呢？
does a matchmaker want to marry?
我的硬性标准是有钱。
Well, my non-negotiables
are that they're rich.
额外要求是对方要让我...
My nice-to-have is that
they're mind-numbingly...
无比...
absurdly...
痛彻心扉地...
achingly...
有钱。
rich.
- 你是在撩我吗？
- (露西大笑)。
- Are you hitting on me?
- (LUCY LAUGHS)
(哈利轻声笑)
(HARRY CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(继续播放舒缓的嘟喔普音乐)。
(SLOW DOO-WOP MUSIC CONTINUING)
(两人轻笑)
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
我们在丽思酒店顶层。
We have the penthouse at the Ritz
准备了派对，想来的话。
for the afterparty, if you want to come.
下次吧。
Maybe next time.
需要我的司机送你吗？
Can my driver drop you somewhere?
有人接我。
I have a ride.
(收音机播放朋克摇滚乐)。
(PUNK ROCK MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
记得这首歌吗？
Remember this one?
嗯。
Yep.
你还住在老地方吗？
You still live in the same place?
约翰：是啊。
JOHN: Yep.
房租还是850美元。
Rent's still $850.
开什么玩笑。
No fucking way.
那破房子都快散架了。
It's falling apart.
我从来用不上热水。
I never get hot water.
露西：你室友们怎么样？
LUCY: How are your roommates?
大卫搬去和未婚妻住了...
David moved in with his fiancee...
我觉得洛根现在
and I think Logan is developing
酗酒成瘾了。
a drinking problem.
露西：大卫订婚了？
LUCY: David is engaged?
对啊。
Yeah.
露西：和那个抖音女孩？
LUCY: To the TikTok girl?
没错。
Yep.
她现在还搞OnlyFans。
She does OnlyFans now too.
他赚到了。
Good for him.
约翰：是吗？
JOHN: Is it?
他是个身高1米7、从没出版过作品
的抑郁小说家。
He's a 5'7" depressed novelist
who's never been published.
他找不到更好的了。
He couldn't do better.
就这么简单？
It's that simple, huh?
这是明摆着的事。
It's just math.
你在想什么？
What are you thinking about?
味道还是老样子。
It smells the same.
约翰：什么，我的车？
JOHN: What, my car?
嗯哼。
Mm-hmm.
- 看那边！
- 我才不花25美元。
- Look, there!
- I'm not going to pay $25
停这破车一小时。
to park this piece of shit for an hour.
这已经是最低价了。
That's the cheapest we'll ever get.
下个街区能找到路边停车位。
We'll find street parking
on the next block.
约翰，都20分钟了。我来付钱吧。
John, it's been 20 minutes.
I'll just pay for it.
不用你付。
You're not paying.
- 我们只能...
- 这些该死的...
- We're going to have to...
- These fucking people...
如果迟到超过15分钟。
forfeit the reservation
预订就作废了
if we're more than 15 minutes late
他们还要收我们
and then they charge us
a cancellation fee of
每人25美元的取消费。
$25 per person.
等等，你是认真的吗？
Wait, are you fucking serious?
我都跟你说过十遍了。
I told you this like 10 times.
这简直是敲诈。
你怎么会订
That's extortion. Why would you make
这种黑店的位置？
a reservation at such a criminal place?
我们说好纪念日
We agreed to go to nice restaurants
要去高档餐厅的。
on our anniversary.
纽约哪有"高档"餐厅不...
Oh, there's no "nice" places
in New York City that won't...
迟到几分钟就收50美元的？
charge you 50 bucks if you're
a couple minutes late?
我们干嘛要开车来？
Why did we even bring the car?
对，都怪我排练拖堂了。
Yes, it's my fault, my rehearsal ran long.
- 你表达得很清楚了。
- 我们本可以叫车的。
- You made your point.
- We could've called a car.
然后花50美元进城...
So we could spend $50
to get into the city...
再在餐厅消费200美元？
and then another $200 at the restaurant?
约翰 你连停车费都付不起
干嘛还要开车？
Why do you have a car
if you can't pay for it, John?
看 就在那儿
Look, right there.
40分钟20美元？
这他妈是什么计价方式？
$20 for 40 minutes?
What the fuck is this math?
我不想在纪念日
I don't want to fight about money
和男朋友为钱吵架。
with my boyfriend on our anniversary.
这让我感觉像在重蹈父母的覆辙。
It makes me feel like my parents.
约翰：对不起行了吧？
JOHN: I'm sorry, okay?
看到下一个停车场我们就停。
We'll park at the next garage we see.
你要干什么？
What are you doing?
露西
Lucy.
你他妈要去哪儿？
Where the fuck are you going?
嘿 我错了还不行吗？
真的对不起
Hey, I'm sorry, all right? I'm sorry.
我身上没钱而且我忘了。
I don't have any money, and I forgot.
什么？忘了什么？
忘了你爱我吗？
What? What did you forget?
That you love me?
能请你回到车里吗？
求你了？
Will you please get back
in the car? Please?
我不想因为贫穷而厌恶你...
I don't want to hate you
because you're poor...
但此刻我就是这样这让我更厌恶自己。
but right now I do,
and it makes me hate myself.
你知道让你开心有多难吗？
Do you know how hard it is
to make you happy?
而我想要你快乐我在努力 真的。
And I want you to be happy.
I'm trying. I really am.
我知道 这份心意
几乎就足以让我快乐了。
I know. And it's almost enough
to make me happy.
(汽车喇叭轰鸣)。
(HORNS BLARING)
多希望我不在乎
五周年纪念日吃路边摊...
I wish that I didn't care
if we ate from a halal cart...
可我就是会在意
on our five-year anniversary, but I do.
不管你有多恨我我保证我更恨自己。
And however much you hate me,
I promise, I hate myself more.
我不恨你
I don't hate you.
你恨的
You do.
这不是因为我们不相爱。
And it's not because we're not in love.
是因为我们太穷了。
It's because we're broke.
(引擎空转轰鸣)。
(ENGINE IDLING LOUDLY)
(轮胎尖锐摩擦声)。
(ENGINE SCREECHES)
(车门开启)
(DOOR OPENS)
(车门关闭)
(DOOR CLOSES)
要上来坐坐吗？
You want to come up?
想
Yes.
但不行
But I shouldn't.
谢谢送我回来
Thanks for the ride.
约翰：随时效劳
JOHN: Anytime.
记得邀请我看你演出。
Invite me to your play.
一定
I will.
(门轴吱呀作响)。
(DOOR CREAKS)
(引擎启动伴随刺耳声)。
(ENGINE STARTS, SCREECHING)
我只是给你些反馈。
I'm just giving you feedback
这样你才能提升服务质量...
so you can improve your performance...
我也能匹配到更优质的对象。
and I can start getting better matches.
我想找个集齐
I want to meet someone
who is a combination of all
前四位匹配对象所有优点的人。
the different awesome parts
of the last four matches.
要像苏菲那样的职业和教育背景。
Sophie's job and education level,
艾米丽的身材和生活品质。
Emily's body and lifestyle,
派珀的容貌和时尚品味...
Piper's face and sense of style...
还要有简那样的兴趣爱好
和电视剧口味
and Jane's hobbies and taste in TV shows.
很简单，
毕竟我可是弗兰肯斯坦博士。
Easy, since I'm Dr. Frankenstein.
(紧张地笑)
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
再过几个月我就48岁了。
I'm turning 48 in a few months
我觉得需要找个更成熟的对象。
and I think I need
to meet someone more grown.
能和我聊得来的，
Someone I can talk to,
最好是懂欣赏音乐、
just a proper woman
who knows good music...
看过老电影的得体女性...
诸如此类。
has seen old movies, things like that.
之前交往的女友都是21、24岁...
My last couple girlfriends
were 21 and 24...
说实话她们有点幼稚。
and they were honestly kind of immature.
(轻声笑)我能想象。
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
I can imagine it might be
和00后女孩相处可能不太容易。
a little hard to relate
to girls born in the 2000s.
我有个非常特别的客户，
I have a really special client,
叫索菲...
her name is Sophie...
她是事业有成的律师，39岁。
she's a highly
accomplished lawyer, she's 39.
呃...
Um...
其实我没考虑30多岁的。
I wasn't really thinking 30s.
露西：所以你说要年长些...
LUCY: So when you said older...
我指的是27、28岁左右。
I meant more like 27, 28.
露西：啊。
LUCY: Ah.
30多岁的女性
It gets really intense and complicated
关系会变得特别复杂。
with women in their 30s.
她们期望值很高
They have really high expectations
而且总急着推进关系，
and they tend to rush things
because I guess,
可能是生物钟在倒计时吧。
their biological clock's ticking.
我还有个很美的客户，31岁——。
I have another really
beautiful client, she's 31--
呃。
Uh.
不要。
No.
最好是...27岁。
Someone... 27.
29岁都算极限了。
Even 29 is pushing it.
相信我——这对大家都好。
Trust me-- it's the best thing
for everyone.
我和20多岁的女孩。
I genuinely get along much better
相处确实更融洽。
with girls in their 20s.
不在乎性格或生活方式...
I don't care what she's like
or how she lives...
只要外形符合我的审美。
I just care that she's my type physically.
露西：你对外形有什么要求？
LUCY: What's your type physically?
身材匀称。
Fit.
露西：就这？
LUCY: Just fit?
体脂率20以下。
Fit. Nothing over 20 BMI.
好吧。
Okay.
谢谢你答应和我约会。
Thank you for agreeing
to come on a date with me.
露西：我只是想让你明白。
LUCY: Well, I only said yes to this
你的想法是错的...
so you'd realize you're wrong...
其实你对我没兴趣。
and you're not actually interested in me.
哈里：我的直觉通常很准。
HARRY: My instincts are usually right.
你觉得你比专业人士。
You think that you're more right
更懂这个？
about this than a professional?
哦当然你是专家，但我相信直觉。
Oh, sure, you're the expert,
but I trust my gut.
露西：行啊，走着瞧。
LUCY: Okay. We'll see.
你今天很美。
You look really good today.
谢谢。
Thanks.
露西：每周喝多少酒？
LUCY: How many drinks per week?
看情况，大概8到10杯？
工作压力大难免会喝。
Depends, but like, 8? 10?
Work makes it hard not to.
- 你吸毒吗？
- 从不。
- Do you do drugs?
- Never.
派对上会抽大麻。
I do pot at parties.
我也是。
Me too.
所以不是从不。
So not never.
嗯。
Hmm.
你觉得你最好看的身体部位是？
What do you think is your
best physical feature?
我的眼睛还不错。
My eyes aren't bad.
你是怎么入行的？
How did you end up doing what you do?
我父母都在金融行业工作...
Both my parents work in finance...
我哥哥也是，
and so does my brother,
所以我就顺其自然地做了这行。
so I just kind of ended up doing it.
我们都在我母亲创立的公司工作。
And we all work for
the firm my mother started.
- 这是家族企业。
- 是啊，挺无聊的。
- It's a family business.
- Yeah, it's boring.
嗯。
Mm.
你是怎么开始现在的工作的？
How did you get into doing what you do?
这是...我第一份也是（轻笑）唯一。
It was the... first
and (CHUCKLES) only thing
真正擅长的事。
I was really good at.
哈里：你还想了解我什么？
HARRY: What else do you want
to know about me?
我打赌你父母从没。
I bet your parents never raised
对彼此大声嚷嚷过。
their voices at each other.
几乎从没有过。
I think almost never.
也许他们只是偷偷吵架。
Maybe they were secretly fighting.
他们为钱吵过架吗？
Did they ever fight about money?
没有。
No.
有道理。
Makes sense.
我觉得我们会模仿父母的吵架方式。
I think we emulate the way
our parents fight.
嗯。
Hmm.
在纽约看到情侣当街吵架。
I see couples fighting
in the middle of the street
我总是不理解。
in New York and I don't get it.
他们不觉得在公众场合这样很丢脸吗？
Aren't they embarrassed to do
that in front of people?
我就是那种会当街吵架的人。
I'm the type to fight
in the middle of the street.
- 是吗？
- 是啊。
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
你这样做过吗？
Have you ever done that?
- 从没有。
- (轻声笑)
- Never.
- (CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
苏菲：你觉得他会喜欢我吗？
SOPHIE: Do you think he will like me?
我觉得你会很喜欢他。
I think you will really like him.
- 你确定？
- 保持开放心态。（笑）
- Are you sure?
- Stay open-minded. (LAUGHS)
- 我好紧张。
- 放轻松。
- I'm so nervous.
- All right.
结束后给我发消息。
Okay, text me after
- 我明天给你打电话。
- 好的。
- and I'll call you tomorrow.
- Okay.
- 好的，晚点聊，苏菲。再见。
- 再见。
- Okay, talk soon, Sophie. Bye.
- Bye.
- 嗨。
- Hi.
- 哇，谢谢。
- (轻声笑)
- Wow. Thank you.
- (CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
不客气。
You're welcome.
你还好吗？
You okay?
没事。我的客户现在也在约会。
Yes. My client is going
on a date right now too.
你看起来很紧张。
You seem nervous.
我真的很希望她喜欢这个男生。
I really want her to like this guy.
她已经连续约会失败十次了。
She's had, like, 10 bad dates in a row
我这次必须得给她找个靠谱的。
and I just need to deliver.
你是因为即将开始完美约会。
Are you feeling guilty that
而感到愧疚吗？
you're about to go on a good date?
（露西轻笑）
(LUCY CHUCKLES)
（模糊的交谈声）
(FAINT INDISTINCT CHATTER)
露西：我不确定是喜欢你。
LUCY: I don't know if I like you
还是单纯喜欢你带我去的地方。
or if I just like the places
you take me to.
你喜欢我？
You like me?
什么时候的事？
When did that happen?
大概是从看你买单的姿势开始的。
I think when I saw the way
you pick up the bill.
（轻声笑）
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
哈利：我这动作很帅吧？
HARRY: I do it really well, don't I?
确实帅
You do.
行云流水一气呵成。
Just one swift motion.
没有犹豫 毫不怯场。
No hesitation. No fear.
哈利：反正我付得起 有什么好怕的。
HARRY: Well, I can afford it,
so why would I be scared?
你在我身上投资不少啊？
You're investing a lot in me, huh?
我只是想让约会更有情调。
I just want our dates to be romantic.
餐费价格决定约会情调？
How expensive a meal is
makes the date romantic?
难道不是吗？
Doesn't it?
初次见面时你说...
When we first met...
你的工作让你活得像个殡葬师。
you said your job makes you
think like a mortician
或是保险理赔员
or an insurance claims adjuster.
那我作为尸体合格吗？
How am I as a corpse?
优质尸体
A good corpse.
那作为理赔金呢？
How about as a payout?
（轻声笑）
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
无可挑剔
Couldn't ask for better.
作为养老院伴侣呢？
As a nursing home partner?
墓友如何？
A grave buddy?
你能找到比我更好的。
You can do better than me.
真的吗？
Can I?
你心里其实算过这笔账吧？
You know how to do the math, don't you?
以我的职业经历...
In my line of work...
见过无数优质男性。
I meet hundreds of highly desirable,
条件都相当出色...
high quality men...
但你是业内所谓的"独角兽"。
but you are what we call
in my industry "a unicorn."
近乎幻想的完美存在。
An impossible fantasy.
你哥哥也是独角兽。
Your brother was a unicorn, too.
我的客户不愿降低标准。
The reason my clients cannot
lower their expectations...
正是因为即便概率渺茫。
is because, against all odds,
像你这样的男人确实存在。
men like you do actually exist.
我肯定有什么致命缺陷。
Well, I'm sure something is wrong with me.
你完美无缺
You're perfect.
聪明睿智
You're smart.
收入学历都无可挑剔...
You have ideal income, ideal education...
生活方式 身高体型...
ideal lifestyle, ideal height...
相貌出众 身材健美。
you're good-looking,
you have a great body,
还魅力非凡
you're charming.
你生来富有，成长环境优渥，
You were born rich, raised rich,
现在依然富有。
you're still rich.
你在翠贝卡区拥有顶层公寓。
You own a penthouse in Tribeca.
你可以带女孩来这样的餐厅用餐。
You can take a girl
to a restaurant like this
甚至都不算（笑）什么特别场合。
and it's not even (LAUGHS)
like a special occasion.
你没有吸毒恶习也不找应召女郎。
You don't have a drug habit
or a call girls habit.
你甚至懂得如何修剪发型，
You even know how to cut your hair,
如何得体着装。
and how to dress.
你很有品味。
You have taste.
你在各方面都是满分十分的存在。
You are a 10 out of 10 in every category.
完美无缺。
A complete package.
所以我不明白为何
要在我这样的人身上。
So I don't know why you're
trying to throw it all away
浪费这一切。
on someone like me.
什么叫你这样的人？
What's someone like you?
就是个普通上班族。
Just a girl who works.
我比你可能约会的对象都要年长。
I'm older than the women
you could be dating.
这意味着我的容貌保质期更短。
Which means my looks won't last as long.
而且我的生育年限所剩无几。
And I have fewer years
left to get pregnant.
如果你娶个25岁的姑娘，
If you marry a 25-year-old,
十年后她才会变成我现在的样子。
then in 10 years she'll look like me.
如果娶我，十年后
我就会变成我妈那样。
If you marry me, in 10 years
I'll look like my mother.
你母亲长什么样？
What does your mother look like?
我出身贫寒，成长环境拮据，
I was born poor, raised poor,
即便现在工作也负债累累。
and even though I work, I have debt.
我是大学辍学生还是失败演员。
I'm a college dropout
and a failed actress.
我没有嫁妆。
I have no dowry.
非要说的话，我的嫁妆是负数。
If anything, I have a negative dowry.
我看起来需要嫁妆吗？
Do I look like I need a dowry?
归根结底，这笔账怎么算都不划算。
At the end of the day,
the math doesn't add up.
考虑到你在婚恋市场的条件
和我的处境，
Given your position in the marketplace
and given mine,
我不是适合结婚的对象。
I'm not a girl you marry.
我是那种你只会带回家一次，
I'm a girl that you go home with once,
之后就再也不联系的人。
and then never call again.
所以...
So...
你为什么要和我在一起？
what are you doing with me?
你说觉得我聪明，
You say you think I'm smart,
可你说话的方式像在对待原始人。
but you're talking to me
like I'm a caveman.
如果看不到价值我不会和你约会。
I wouldn't date you if I didn't see value.
我和我哥哥不一样。
I'm not like my brother.
我不是在找最温柔漂亮、
I'm not looking for the nicest,
家境优越又喜欢我的女孩。
prettiest rich girl who likes me back.
我要找的是懂游戏规则、
I'm looking for someone
who understands the game,
明白世界运转之道的人。
how the world works.
我在寻找让我敬重的人。
I'm looking for someone I respect.
并且信任的人。
And trust.
比我见识更广的人。
Someone who knows more than me.
我和你约会不是图物质条件...
I don't want to date you
for your material assets...
虽然我觉得你严重低估了。
though I think you're underselling them
自己的这些优势。
by a significant margin.
物质条件根本不值钱，
Material assets are cheap,
它们不会长久。
they don't last.
我想和你在一起
是因为你的无形资产。
I want to be with you
for your intangible assets.
那些才是优质投资。
Those are good investments.
它们不会贬值，只会越来越珍贵。
They don't degrade. They only get sharper.
再说了，我的物质资产足够。
And, besides,
I have enough material assets
我们两个人用。
for the both of us.
我在你身上看到巨大潜力。
I see a lot of potential here.
我觉得我们可以成为绝佳搭档。
I think you and I could make
great partners.
希望你也这么认为。
I hope you agree.
至于我能为你做些什么...
As for what I can do for you...
我想我是唯一一个这么有钱。
I think I'm the only guy this rich
却还能让你不反感的人。
you can actually stand.
我喜欢你不是因为你有钱。
I don't like you because you're rich.
那你为什么喜欢我？
Then why do you like me?
因为你让我觉得自己有价值。
Because you make me feel valuable.
你本来就有价值。
You are valuable.
这正是我想告诉你的。
That's what I'm trying to tell you.
要不要更认真地交往看看？
Do you want to see
each other more seriously?
- (性感独立音乐播放)
- (电梯叮咚声)。
- (SENSUAL INDIE MUSIC PLAYING)
- (ELEVATOR DINGS)
(哈利轻声呻吟)。
(HARRY MOANS SOFTLY)
(露西笑声)
(LUCY LAUGHING)
(手机震动声)
(PHONE VIBRATING)
- (电话铃声)
- (模糊的交谈声)。
- (LINE RINGING)
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(电话铃声)
(LINE RINGING)
语音信箱：您好，这里是
爱之约婚介公司的露西。
VOICEMAIL: Hi, you've reached
Lucy from Adore Matchmaking.
请留言
Please leave a message
我会尽快回复。
谢谢。
and I'll call you back. Thanks.
- (哔声)- 嘿，我是约翰。
- (BEEPS)
- Hey, it's John.
收到留言后给我回个电话。
Okay. Just give me a call
when you get this.
想邀请你来看话剧。
Just wanted to invite you to the play.
下周开始预演，所以...
We start previews next week, so...
好，再见。
Okay. Bye.
哈利：你梦想的度假地是哪里？
HARRY: What's your dream vacation?
冰岛。
Iceland.
嗯。
Hmm.
(轻声叹息)
(SIGHS SOFTLY)
愿意让我带你去冰岛吗？
Would you let me take you to Iceland?
- 我连护照都没有。
- 那我们去办一个。
- I don't even have a passport.
- Well, let's get you one.
(轻笑)
(CHUCKLES)
(叹息)
(SIGHING)
(耳语)这公寓多少钱？
(WHISPERING) How much is this apartment?
一千两百万。
Twelve million.
(耳语)喜欢吗？
(WHISPERING) Do you like it?
(轻声笑)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
- (闹钟响)- (远处警笛声)。
- (ALARM RINGING)
- (SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE)
(约翰呻吟，叹气)。
(JOHN GROANS, SIGHS)
- (橡胶挤压声)- 哦。
- (RUBBER SQUELCHES)
- Oh.
搞什么鬼？
What the fuck?
(恼怒地叹气)
(SIGHS IN EXASPERATION)
该死！
Fuck!
(吧唧声)
(SQUELCHING)
- (重击声)- 喂，混蛋！
- (THUDS)
- Hey, motherfucker!
你不能把用过的避孕套
丢在厨房地板上！
You can't leave your used condoms
on the kitchen floor!
这太不像话了！
It's unacceptable!
我昨晚有点喝多了。
I got kind of drunk last night.
可能没扔进垃圾桶。
I must've missed the trash can.
你怎么不扔到你自己的垃圾桶里？
Why don't you throw it out
in your own fucking trash can?
我不想让那玩意儿一直摆在房间里。
I don't want it just
sitting there in the room.
为什么不想让你自己的
精液留在房间？
Why don't you want
your own cum in the room?
太他妈恶心了。
It's fucking gross.
所以我们就得在
该死的厨房里看到它？
So we have to deal with it
in the fucking kitchen?
我知道这说不通
老兄，我当时喝醉了。
I know it doesn't
make sense, man, I was drunk.
罗恩：嘿，你们俩能别嚷嚷了吗？
RON: Hey, can you two stop yelling?
我正在Zoom上教表演课...
I'm teaching an acting class on Zoom...
你们让我显得特别不专业。
and you're making me
look really unprofessional.
(摔门声)
(DOOR SLAMS)
(重击声)
(THUDS)
(叹气)
(SIGHS)
哦，该死！
Oh, fuck!
(轻微撞击声，吱呀声)。
(THUDS LIGHTLY, CREAKS)
(撞击声，吱呀声)。
(THUDS, CREAKS)
(叹气)
(SIGHS)
哈里：好吧。
HARRY: Right.
所以他在梦里要求估值。
So he's asking for
a valuation in his dreams.
这是虚高的。
It's inflated.
他给我们的现金流折现
完全基于虚构...
He's giving us a DCF
based on pure fiction...
对未来收入流的预测
却无视费用增长。
on future revenue streams with
blinders for expense growth.
没错，他是个糟糕的分析师...
Yeah, he's a bad analyst...
现在根本就是在胡编乱造。
and he's just making
shit up at this point.
他只是随口编数字。听着...
He's just saying numbers that
come to his head. Listen...
这对我们公司来说
仍是个不错的增长故事...
it's still a good growth
story for our company...
所以我们还得继续。
so we're going to have to continue
陪这家伙玩下去。
playing ball with this guy.
(电话铃声)
(LINE RINGING)
语音信箱：您好，我是索菲...
VOICEMAIL: Hi, you've reached Sophie...
(叹气)
(SIGHS)
(电话铃声)
(LINE RINGING)
马克：喂？
MARK: Hello?
嗨，马克我是Adore的露西。
Hi, Mark, it's Lucy from Adore.
马克：哦，你好。
MARK: Oh, hi.
你好。我想了解一下。
Hi. So, I just wanted to get some feedback
你和我客户索菲第一次约会的情况。
on your first date with my client Sophie.
其实我还没联系上她...
Actually I haven't gotten
ahold of her yet...
所以不知道她那边感觉如何...
so I don't know how it went on her end...
但我很期待听听你的感受。
but I'm excited to hear
how it went for you.
马克：进展太顺利了。
她真的很棒。
MARK: It went so well. She's wonderful.
长相出众，身材也很好，
Like really nice face, good body,
工作体面，充满活力。
good job, great energy.
完全符合我理想中的匹配标准。
Just all the things I said
I wanted from a match.
好的。
Okay.
太好了，我就爱听这个。
Okay, I love hearing this.
真高兴你们相处愉快。
Um, I'm so glad you had a good time.
苏菲确实很优秀。
Sophie is really wonderful.
马克：是啊。
MARK: Yeah, no.
我们聊得特别投机。
Like the conversation just flowed.
最后还在外面待到很晚。
Uh, we ended up staying out pretty late.
不错啊。那你想再约她吗？
Cool. So, do you want to see her again?
马克：当然。
MARK: Sure.
不过不确定会不会认真发展...
Sure. I'm not sure how serious
it's going to be...
但如果她愿意，我不介意再见她。
but I wouldn't mind seeing
her again, if she's game.
很好，慢慢来嘛。
Great. Yeah, of course,
one step at a time.
马克：好的。谢谢你，露西。
MARK: All right. Thanks, Lucy.
祝你今天愉快
Great. You have a good day
我下午联系你...
and I'll reach out this afternoon...
等我先和她聊聊。
谢谢，马克。
after I speak with her. Thanks, Mark.
谢谢你，马克！
Thanks, Mark!
(叹气)
(SIGHS)
语音信箱：嘿，我是约翰。
VOICEMAIL: Hey, it's John.
听到留言给我回个电话。
Okay. Just give me a call
when you get this.
想邀请你来看话剧。
Just wanted to invite you to the play.
语音信箱：你好，这里是苏菲...
VOICEMAIL: Hi, you've reached Sophie...
- 嗨。
- Hey.
罗丝在问她的客户米娅·W的情况，
So, uh, Rose was asking
for her client Mia W.
和彼得·C的弟弟哈里进展如何？
How it's going with
Peter C.'s brother, Harry?
你成功招募他了吗？
Were you able to recruit him?
嗯...其实呢...
Yeah. Uh, actually, um...
我们在交往。
I'm dating him.
- 你们在交往？
- 对。
- You're dating him?
- Yep.
- 你知道他是稀有资源。
- 嗯哼。
- You know he's a unicorn.
- Mm-hmm.
(轻笑)
(CHUCKLES)
就不能先让他
You couldn't let him go on a couple dates
和我们其他客户约会几次吗？
with some of our clients first?
是他坚持的。
He insisted.
黛西：(嗤笑)我信他才怪。
DAISY: (SCOFFS) I'm sure he did.
露西，能来我办公室谈谈吗？
Hey, Lucy. Can I speak to you
in my office?
你和苏菲·L联系过了吗？
Have you spoken with Sophie L.?
还没，只联系了马克·P。
Uh, not yet. Just Mark P.
维奥莱特：我刚和苏菲的律师通完话。
VIOLET: I just hung up
with Sophie's lawyer.
她的律师？
Her lawyer?
据说她在约会中遭到了侵犯。
Apparently, she was assaulted on the date.
什么？
What?
马克·P干的？
By Mark P.?
维奥莱特：是的。
VIOLET: Yes.
昨晚的事？
Last night?
你是认真的吗？
Are you serious?
她起诉的是公司，不是你。
She's bringing charges
to the company, not you.
两分钟后我要和法律团队通话...
I have a call with the legal team
in two minutes...
我们会解决这个问题的。
and we're going to figure it out.
我必须和她谈谈。
I need to speak with her.
露西，不行。
Lucy, no.
- 维奥莱特，她是我的客户。
- 维奥莱特：现在不是了。
- Violet, she's my client.
- VIOLET: She's not anymore.
如果索菲打电话来，你绝对不能接。
So if Sophie calls, you must not pick up.
- 我不能袖手旁观。
- 维奥莱特：就袖手旁观。
- I can't do nothing.
- VIOLET: Do nothing.
根据你掌握的信息。
You made the best match you could
你已经尽力做了最佳匹配。
given the information you have.
这次配对确实出了问题。
This particular match did not work out
但几个月来你为索菲做的
匹配工作一直很出色。
but you've been doing
amazing work for Sophie for months.
不是"出了问题"这么简单，维，
The match didn't "not work out," Vi,
她是被侵犯了。
she was assaulted.
媒人无法担保一个人。
A matchmaker can't vouch
for how a person is
在亲密场合的表现。
in an intimate setting
因为她从未和他们有过亲密接触。
since she's never been in one with them.
以前发生过类似的事吗？
Has something like this happened before?
当然。
Of course.
这就是约会。
This is dating.
我工作的第三年
This happened to one of my clients
就有客户遇到过这种事。
the third year I worked here.
做这行久了，大家都会碰到。
If you do this long enough,
it happens to all of us.
这是已知风险。
It's a known risk.
(低沉的音乐)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(嘈杂的交谈声)。
(OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
(门吱呀打开)
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
(吱呀声，关门，落锁)。
(CREAKS, CLOSES, LATCHES)
(倒吸冷气)
(GASPING)
(呼吸颤抖)
(BREATH TREMBLING)
嗨，你好。
Hi, you.
你好。
Hi.
抱歉我迟到了。
Sorry I'm late.
没关系。
No worries.
我穿得够得体吗？
Am I dressed nice enough?
可能有点太正式了。
You might be dressed too nice.
我的父母相爱了。
My mother and father made love.
我出生，长大。
I was born. I grew up.
走进这家餐厅，正在约会。
I entered this restaurant. I'm on a date.
服务员走过来问我。
A waiter walks up to me and asks,
"需要点什么？"。
"What can I do for you?"
"不知道，你能提供什么？"。
"I don't know. What can you do for me?"
我点了杯水。
I order a glass of water.
我的父母相爱了。
My mother and father made love.
我出生，长大。
I was born. I grew up.
走进这家餐厅，正在约会。
I entered this restaurant. I'm on a date.
服务员的手正搭在我背上。
The waiter is touching my back.
(观众笑声)
(AUDIENCE LAUGHS)
我上学读书。
I went to school. I read books.
写过读书报告。
I wrote book reports.
我上了更多学。
写了论文。
I went to more school. I wrote essays.
约翰：嗯，确实与众不同。
JOHN: Well, it's certainly different.
我是说，这个，呃...
I mean, it's, it's, uh...
这是段很棒的经历。
我觉得自己很幸运。
It's been a good experience.
I feel really lucky.
听着，认识你们真的很开心。
Listen, it was great to meet you guys.
- 谢谢你们能来。
- 男士：当然。
- Thanks for coming.
- MAN: Of course.
- 嘿，老兄。
- 嘿。
- Hey, buddy.
- Hey.
- 太精彩了。
- 真的吗？
- That was great.
- Was it?
是的，我非常喜欢。
Yes, I loved it.
这是我男朋友哈利。
This is my boyfriend, Harry.
嗨，很高兴认识你。
谢谢你能来。
Hey, nice to meet you. Thanks for coming.
恭喜你。
演出非常有意思。
Congratulations.
That was really interesting.
谢谢。
Thanks.
真不敢相信你记住了所有台词。
I can't believe you remembered
all those lines.
是啊，简直疯了。
Yeah. Yeah, it's nuts.
听着，我们准备去。
Well, listen, we're going around
转角那家店喝一杯。
the corner to get a drink.
你们要一起来吗？
You guys want to come?
- 好啊。
- 太棒了。
- Yes.
- Great.
- 好的。
- 没问题。
- Okay.
- Yeah.
约翰：说真的，你觉得怎么样？
JOHN: So, what did you really think?
我喜欢。
I liked it.
有些部分不太明白...
Some of it didn't make sense...
但我超爱看你表演，你知道的。
but I loved watching you act,
you know that.
你有怀念过演戏吗？
Do you ever miss it?
露西：演戏？没有。
LUCY: Acting? No.
一点点都没有？
Not even a little bit?
露西：我和你不一样。
LUCY: I'm not like you.
我从来就没想过当演员。
I was never going to be an actor.
我连怎么站姿或...说话都不会。
I didn't know how to stand or... speak.
但你一直都很棒。
You were always good though.
现在更出色了。
You're even better now.
我真的很为你骄傲，约翰。
I'm really proud of you, John.
- （模糊的交谈声）
- （愉快的音乐声）
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- (PLEASANT MUSIC PLAYING)
你在婚礼上认识他的？
You met him at the wedding?
露西：对。
LUCY: Yeah.
他是新郎的弟弟。
He's the groom's brother.
你不会要嫁给他吧？
You're not gonna marry him, are you?
为什么不呢？
Why not?
因为他长得帅。
Because he's good-looking.
还很有钱。
And rich.
有正经工作。
Has a real job.
估计都不用跟人合租。
Probably doesn't have roommates.
大概也不会整天
Probably doesn't get angry
为些无关紧要的破事发火。
at stupid shit all the time
that doesn't matter.
我们能聊点别的吗？
Can we talk about something else?
你还好吗？
You okay?
为什么这么问？
Why do you ask?
就是...你看起来不太对劲。
Just... you don't seem like you're okay.
是因为他吗？
Is it him?
这能行吗？
Is it work?
我只是觉得自己
工作能力越来越差了。
I just don't think I'm very good
at my job anymore.
(叹气)
(SIGHS)
我相信会好起来的。
I'm sure it's gonna be fine.
你对自己太苛刻了。
You're so hard on yourself.
你又不是无人机驾驶员
或枪支游说者。
You're not a drone pilot
or a gun lobbyist.
也没在壳牌或麦肯锡工作。
You don't work at Shell or McKinsey.
只是约会而已没那么严重。
It's just dating. It's not that serious.
是啊。
Right.
约会不算正经事。
Dating is not serious.
不过是女生的小把戏对吧？
It's just girl shit, right?
我不是这个意思。
That's not what I meant.
你总是知道该怎么安慰我。
You always know exactly what to say to me.
哈里：准备好了吗？
HARRY: Ready to go?
嗯 我在外面等你。
Yep. I'm gonna wait for you outside.
哈里：呃我去拿饮料。
HARRY: Uh, I'll get the drinks.
贝丝：(惊喜)谢谢你哈里。
BETH: (GASPS) Thank you, Harry.
谢谢。
Thank you.
- (远处嘈杂声)- (警笛声)。
- (RATTLING IN DISTANCE)
- (SIREN WAILS)
(叹气)
(SIGHS)
我不想和自由派约会。
I don't want to date a liberal
而且对方必须每周日都去教堂。
and they have to go to church
every Sunday.
我不要喜欢猫的人。
I don't want someone who likes cats.
我是爱狗人士。
I'm a dog person.
露西：温和派民主党人可以吗？
LUCY: Is a moderate democrat okay?
只要共和党人。
Only republican.
我要认同保守主义的人。
I want someone who identifies
as a conservative.
露西：奥黛丽(叹气)我不知道。
LUCY: Audrey, (SIGHS) I don't know
纽约大部分地区有没有讨厌猫的。
if there's a cat-hating,
Christian conservative lesbian
基督教保守派女同...
in most parts of New York...
愿意和49岁深柜。
who wants to date a closeted
带着三个孩子的人约会。
49-year-old with three children.
你愿意考虑
Would you be willing to date someone
长岛或新泽西的人吗？
from Long Island or New Jersey?
我想优先考虑白人男性。
I want to prioritize dating a man
作为第一选择
who's white at first
如果实在找不到再考虑其他种族。
but then if we have no luck,
we can move on to other races.
露西：所以先"仅限白人"？
LUCY: So "whites only," at first?
理论上说我对所有种族都开放。
I mean, technically,
I'm open to all ethnicities.
埃莉诺"理论上"来说。
Eleanor, "technically,"
你是在让我只给你介绍白人男性。
you're asking me to set you up
with only white men.
我知道要求很多但我值得拥有。
I know the list looks long
but I deserve someone
完全符合条件的人。
who fulfills all of my criteria.
真的值得。
I really do.
看看我我可是抢手货。(轻笑)。
I mean look at me. I'm a catch. (CHUCKLES)
帕特里夏我知道每单身一年。
Patricia, I know that every year
你对未来丈夫的期待值。
you go without having a husband...
就会指数级增长。
raises your expectations
for him exponentially.
但这不意味着
你注定会得到理想对象。
But that doesn't mean
that you're due to get one.
也不代表你可以
定制一个完美丈夫...
And it doesn't mean
that you can customize...
因为这并不是一场模拟游戏。
because this is not a simulation.
如果我提供的服务。
If the service I was providing you
是为你定制一个完美男人。
was building you a man then, of course,
我当然可以按照清单打造出符合所有
条件的人选...
I could build you a man with
everything on this list...
但我做不到。
But I can't.
因为这不是买车或买房。
Because this is not a car or a house.
我们谈论的是活生生的人。
We're talking about people.
人就是人，本性难移。
People are people are people are people.
每个人都带着与生俱来的特质。
They come as they are.
我能为你争取的最好结果。
And all I can hope to find for you
就是找个你能勉强忍受的男人。
is a man that you can tolerate
在未来50年里不讨厌你的那种。
for the next 50 years
who likes you at all.
而你也不是什么抢手货...
And you are not a catch...
因为你根本不是商品。
because you are not a fish.
我只是在帮她认清现实。
I was managing her expectations.
维奥莱特：帕特里夏取消了会员。
VIOLET: Patricia canceled her membership
还在网上骂我们是骗子机构。
and reviewed us online, calling us a scam.
我们确实是骗子。
We are a scam.
根本没兑现承诺，不是吗？
We don't give them
what they pay for, do we?
我们许诺给她们真爱。
We promise them love and then...
结果只安排了和蠢货罪犯的糟糕约会。
we just give them bad dates
with morons and criminals.
我知道索菲的事让你压力很大。
I know the Sophie L. situation
is still weighing on you.
红娘职业倦怠很常见。
Burnout is common for matchmakers.
你需要休息。
You need a break.
该和男朋友去度个假。
You should go on a trip
with your boyfriend.
（嗤笑）
(SCOFFS)
如果现在停下...
If I take a break right now...
可能就再也回不来了。
I may never come back.
维奥莱特：你会回来的
，因为你爱这些客户。
VIOLET: You will,
because you love your clients.
我恨他们。都是些巨婴。
I hate them. They are children.
我恨透他们了。
I hate them.
维奥莱特：他们付了上万美元。
VIOLET: They give us thousands of dollars.
有权表现得幼稚点。
They're entitled to some regression.
你觉得他们当中
Do you think that any one of them
有人会对心理医生说...
says to their therapist...
"不要黑人，不要胖子"吗？
"No Blacks, no fatties"?
要是我真成了他们的心理医生。
And if I'm their actual therapist,
虽然现在也差不多了...
which it feels like I am...
我可没受过专业训练。
I don't have the schooling
to support that.
工资也远远不够。
And I certainly don't get paid enough.
维奥莱特：露西，
我们比心理医生更厉害。
VIOLET: Lucy, we're better
than therapists.
我们接触的是最私密。
We work with the most intimate...
最难以启齿的
extremely personal,
他们人生中见不得光。
unofficial part of their lives...
恨不得彻底删除的部分。
that they'd like to see
struck from the record.
我们直面他们的孤独与挫败。
We work with their
loneliness and rejection...
那种让人在陌生人面前脱光的脆弱。
the kind that makes someone
get naked for a stranger.
我们才是真正的灵魂摆渡人。
We're the real deal.
所以他们才会告诉你。
That's why they tell you
连心理医生都不知道的秘密。
more than they would tell their therapists
以及他们为何愿意为你冒险。
and why they take risks with you.
"冒险"。
"Risks."
维奥莱特：没错。那些可能导致
像索菲·L事件的风险。
VIOLET: Yes. Risks that can
lead to a situation
也可能促成
like what happened with Sophie L.
相伴终生的婚姻。
And risks that lead to lifelong marriages.
你知道这份工作能改变人生。
You know this is life-changing work.
而你天生就该做这个。
And you're born for it.
从现在开始休假吧。
Take a break starting now.
我希望四周后回来时你能焕然一新。
And I expect you back
in four weeks, renewed.
这是命令。
I insist.
- (欢呼声)- (敲门声)。
- (CHEERING)
- (KNOCK ON DOOR)
萝丝：维奥莱特！天大的好消息！
ROSE: Violet! Amazing news!
我的客户佐伊·H
和弗雷德·A订婚了！
My client Zoe H.
and Fred A. just got engaged!
(女人们欢呼)
(WOMEN CHEERING)
维奥莱特：太难以置信了！天啊！
VIOLET: Unbelievable! Oh!
这简直太棒了！
That is so impressive!
多么完美的一对！
What an amazing match!
- 第四对了？
- (叹息)
- Number four?
- (SIGHS)
- 萝丝：没错！
- 我们必须给你办个派对！
- ROSE: Yes!
- We have to throw you a party!
(女人们尖叫)
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
(忧郁的音乐)
(SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
(紧张的音乐)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(男人交谈声)
(MAN CHATTERING)
露西：索菲。
LUCY: Sophie.
(模糊的交谈声)。
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(喘息)索菲。
(PANTING) Sophie.
- 索菲。
- 你不想和我说话。
- Sophie.
- You don't want to talk to me.
求你了。
Please.
我太羞愧了。
I am so embarrassed.
我居然以为花钱雇人。
I thought I could pay some girl
就能找到真爱。
to find me a boyfriend.
对不起。
I'm sorry.
"专家"？
真是天大的笑话。
"An expert"? What a fucking joke.
- 索菲-
- 知道更可笑的是什么吗？
- Sophie-
- You know what's even funnier?
我差点以为我们成了朋友。
I almost felt like we were friends.
我...我...我真的...
I, I, I, I really-- I--
(呼吸颤抖)
(BREATH TREMBLING)
我们能谈谈吗？
Can we please just talk?
谈什么？
Talk about what?
你还有什么可说的？
What do you have to say?
(叹息，低语)对不起。
(SIGHS, WHISPERING) I'm sorry.
(正常声音)我真的很抱歉。
(IN NORMAL VOICE) I'm so sorry.
我曾信任你。
I trusted you.
我不知道他会做出这种事。
I didn't know what he was capable of.
所以你的意思是...
I see, so...
你知道他的身高——
顺便说这也是谎报的。
you knew his height,
which was a lie by the way.
还有他的工作和薪水。
And his job and his salary,
同样也都是假的我得说明白。
which was also a lie just for the record.
还有他那张脸其实也不怎么样...
And his looks, which is
really nothing much...
但你却不了解他的人品。
but you didn't know who he was.
作为一个人，一个男人。
As a person. As a man.
我和他约会后才发现。
Well, I went on a date
with him and found out.
他是那种喝醉酒
He's the kind of guy who gets drunk
会尾随你进洗手间的人。
and follows you into the bathroom.
（叹气）
(SIGHS)
你怎么能给我介绍这种人？
Why would you set me up
with someone like that?
他条件优秀潜力十足。
He was a strong match
with a lot of potential.
符合我们多项匹配标准。
He checked a lot of our boxes.
「标准」？
"Boxes"?
你给我安排这种对象。
The truth is, you set me up with that man
就是觉得我一文不值。
because you think I'm worthless.
露西：不，我没有——。
LUCY: No, I don't--
你根本不知道该怎么安置我。
You didn't know what to do with me.
所以才会促成那次约会。
That's how I ended up on that date.
我还以为你是为我工作...
Here I was thinking that
you worked for me...
结果一直都是我在替你打工。
but the whole time I was working for you.
滞销商品...
Worthless merchandise...
随便找个接盘的人脱手。
to pawn off to anyone who'd take it.
但我不是商品。
But I am not merchandise.
我是活生生的人。
I'm a person.
我知道自己值得被爱。（抽泣）
And I know I deserve love. (SHUDDERS)
你当然值得，我坚信这点。
I know you do. I believe it.
去你的。
Fuck you.
皮条客。
Pimp.
（啜泣）
(SOBBING)
（撞击声）
(THUDS)
（吸鼻子）
(SNIFFLES)
- （手机震动）-谢谢。
- (PHONE VIBRATING)
- Thanks.
能给我收据吗？
Can I get a receipt?
- （手机震动）-（
电台西班牙语对话）
- (PHONE VIBRATING)
- (SPANISH CHATTER ON RADIO)
（手机持续震动）
(PHONE CONTINUES VIBRATING)
谢了兄弟。
Thanks, man.
露西？
Lucy?
发生什么事？你还好吗？
What's going on? You okay?
露西：（颤抖）不好。
LUCY: (SHUDDERING) No.
要我去接你吗？
Do you want me to come get you?
露西：不用，我在家。
LUCY: No, I'm at home.
我本不该打给你的。
I shouldn't even be calling you.
随时都可以找我。怎么了？
You can always call me. What's up?
露西：我搞砸了。（抽噎）
LUCY: I fucked up. (SOBS)
没事。
Okay.
按规定不能告诉别人...
I'm not supposed to tell anybody but...
但能跟你说吗？
can I tell you?
约翰：当然。
JOHN: Of course.
任何事都可以。
Anything.
我给客户介绍了人渣。
I set my client up with a bad person.
当时不知道他品行不端。
I didn't know he was bad,
but I introduced them.
现在
And now
我无力挽回。
I can't fix it.
我是最没资格补救的人。
I'm the last person who can fix it.
需要我过来陪你吗？
Do you want me to come over?
露西：不用。
LUCY: No.
不用 我正准备去哈里那儿。
No. I'm about to go to Harry's.
好吧。
Right.
露西：抱歉。
LUCY: Sorry.
别这么说 这没什么好道歉的。
No, no. It's... Hey,
nothing to be sorry about.
继续跟我说说发生了什么。
Keep telling me what happened.
我在这儿呢。
I'm here.
(流水声)
(WATER RUNNING)
(哈里叹息)
(HARRY SIGHS)
你知道这些是什么吗？
Do you know what they are?
大概知道。
I think so.
- 不是什么大事- 我明白。
- It's not a big deal.
- I know.
我做了项投资。
I made an investment.
身体就像一套公寓。
A body is like an apartment.
必须投入才能获得回报。
You have to invest to get the value back.
我懂你的意思。
I understand you.
我也投资过。
I invested too.
哈里：嗯 我猜也是。
HARRY: Right. I figured.
你弟弟也做了？
Did your brother too?
哈里：对 我们八年前一起做的。
HARRY: Yeah, we did it
together eight years ago.
夏洛特择偶标准里写着
身高必须超过一米八...
Six feet or taller was one of
Charlotte's non-negotiables...
所以我很庆幸做了手术。
so I'm glad he did.
当时疼吗？
Was it painful?
我知道听起来很蠢，
I know it sounds stupid,
打断腿骨就为了增高几厘米。
breaking your legs to gain
a few extra inches.
但我们一直说绝对值得。
But we keep saying, definitely worth it.
这改变了我们的人生。
It changed our lives.
在异性缘方面当然特别明显。
With women, completely, of course.
现在会有女生主动搭讪，
Women just approach us and talk to us now,
以前从没这种待遇。
which never happened before.
从那以后我就没失手过。
I haven't struck out since.
但你在职场和社交场合。
But you can also tell
the difference at work
餐厅 机场都能感受到差别。
and at restaurants and airports. You're...
你就是...更受重视了。
You're just worth more.
这会影响我们吗？
Does this change anything?
不会。
No.
(叹息)
(SIGHS)
你在想什么？
What are you thinking about?
我在想...
I'm thinking that...
你应该自己一个人去冰岛。
that you should go to Iceland without me.
- 为什么？
- (叹息)
- Why?
- (SIGHS)
我觉得我们并不合适。
I don't think that you and I
are a good match.
(叹息)
(SIGHS)
是因为我做过手术？
Is it because I got the surgery?
不 知道这事反而让我感觉
真正了解了你。
No. Knowing that just makes me
feel like I actually know you.
那是为什么？
Then what?
我很难不觉得
It's really hard for me to feel like
这事和你的腿有关。
this is not about the legs.
不是这样的。
It's not.
当我意识到你的所作所为时。
When I realized what you had done,
那种感觉和我之前对你的感受完全一样。
it made me feel exactly
how I felt about you before.
什么感受？
Which is what?
我并不爱你。
I'm not in love with you.
你也不爱我。
And you're not in love with me.
再多的钱也改变不了这个事实。
And there's no amount of money
that can fix that.
但我们明明很般配。
But we're such a good match.
你完全符合我的择偶标准...
You're exactly what I'm looking for...
而且我能让你的生活变得更好。
and I know I can make your life better.
哈利，你并不是想娶我。
Harry, you don't want to marry me.
你是想和我做生意。
You want to do business with me,
就像我想和你做生意一样。
just like I want to do business with you.
但婚姻不就是一桩生意吗？
But isn't marriage a business deal?
确实如此。
Yes, it is.
当你真正爱上一个人时就不会了。
But love has to be on the table.
如果我没有爱的能力呢？
What if I'm not capable of it?
你是说不会爱人？
Of love?
这让我觉得自己像个白痴。
It makes me feel like an idiot.
就像个...
Like I'm...
什么都不懂的...小孩子。
I'm just a clueless... child.
光是想到爱情...
I feel so... dumb thinking about it...
或是渴望爱情
or wanting it.
就让我觉得...
I find it...
特别困难。
so difficult.
(叹气)
You won't, when you love someone.
(SIGHS)
一切都会变得很简单。
It'll be easy.
不需要算计。
No math.
我该雇佣你的婚介服务吗？
Should I hire you for your services?
如果你打电话到公司。
If you call the office,
他们会为你安排最优秀的顾问。
they'll assign someone great for you.
(深吸气，叹气)。
(INHALES, SIGHS)
就这样结束了？
So this is it?
你想知道我长高了多少英寸？
You want to know how many inches?
对啊。
Yeah.
六英寸。
Six.
你原来只有5尺6寸？
You were 5'6" before?
要是只有这个身高。
I wouldn't have had the confidence
我可没自信来搭讪你。
to hit on you at 5'6".
你肯定会的。
I'm sure you would have.
我还是你的独角兽吗？
Am I still a unicorn?
你完美无缺。
You're perfect.
(司机说俄语)
(DRIVER SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
- (机器运转声)- (门铃声)。
- (WHIRRING)
- (DOORBELL RINGING)
约翰：我的充电器呢？
JOHN: Where's my charger?
(手机铃声)
(CELL PHONE PLAYING)
嘿，那是我的充电器吗？
Hey, is that my charger?
罗根：我的充电器坏了。
LOGAN: My charger broke.
所以你就直接拿我的？
我还设了闹钟呢。
So you just took mine? I had an alarm set.
你他妈这辈子能不能开一次门！
And answer the fucking door
for once in your fucking life!
- (门铃声)- 什么？
- (DOORBELL RINGING)
- What?
嗨，我是露西。
Hi. It's Lucy.
对不起。
I'm sorry.
不不，没关系我只是——。
No, no, that's okay. I was just--
我这就下来。
I'll come down there.
等我一下别走开。
Just give me-- Just don't move.
(手机铃声)
(CELL PHONE PLAYING)
嘿，搞什么鬼？
Hey, what the fuck?
哦...
Oh...
- (物品掉落声)- 嘘...
- (OBJECTS CLATTERING)
- Sh...
该死的。
Goddamn it.
(流水声)
(WATER RUNNING)
靠。
Fuck.
嗨。
Hi.
露西：嗨。
LUCY: Hi.
(约翰叹气)
(JOHN SIGHS)
你楼上藏了姑娘？
You have a girl up there?
什么？没有你怎么会这么想？
What? No. Why would you say that?
不知道 你不让我上去啊(笑)。
I don't know. You didn't want
me to come up. (LAUGHS)
哦 对 没有楼上没姑娘。
Oh. Yeah, no, there's no girl up there.
抱歉突然来找你。
Sorry for showing up without warning.
我打过电话。
I tried calling.
抱歉 我手机没电了。
Sorry. My phone wasn't charged.
我本该在去冰岛的飞机上。
I'm meant to be on a plane to Iceland.
好吧。
Okay.
我把公寓短租出去了。
I sublet my apartment for the week
本来这周该在冰岛的...
that I'm supposed to be in Iceland...
所以我现在没地方住。
so I, uh, don't have a place to stay.
抱歉 我也不知道为什么来这里。
Sorry, I don't know what I'm doing here.
- 这太莫名其妙了- 不 不会。
- It doesn't make any sense.
- No, no.
- 我以为这很合理
- 等等 别走 留下来。
- I thought it made sense.
- Wait, wait. Don't go. Stay.
这是个馊主意。
This was a bad idea.
不 只是...
No, it's not. It's just...
我的公寓实在...
My apartment is not...
不适合你。
suitable for you.
以前就挺适合的。
It was suitable before.
是啊 但我们都不是二十多岁了。
Yeah, well, we're not in our 20s anymore.
我知道你公寓什么样。
I know what your apartment is like.
相信我 比记忆中还糟。
Trust me, it's worse than you remember.
要开车去郊外吗？
Want to drive upstate?
去哪儿？
And go where?
不知道 就随便开。
I don't know. Just drive around.
住酒店。
Stay at a hotel.
我刚拿到话剧的津贴。
I just got the stipend from my play,
所以...感觉挺阔绰的。
so... I'm feeling rich.
(轻柔的背景音乐)。
(SOFT EMOTIONAL MUSIC PLAYING)
约翰：在想什么？
JOHN: What are you thinking about?
你还是一点没变。
You're the same as always.
真的吗？
Really?
露西：嗯哼。
LUCY: Mm-hmm.
我本来希望你会说我很特别。
I was hoping you'd say I was different.
露西：为什么？
LUCY: Why?
因为如果我与众不同，
Because if I'm different,
我就不会成为那个失去你的人。
then I wouldn't be the guy that lost you.
(轻笑)
(CHUCKLES)
露西：什么？
LUCY: What?
那是我的餐饮公司。
That's my catering company.
你觉得他们会让我们进去吗？
Do you think they'd get us in?
(众人惊呼)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(全体鼓掌)
(ALL APPLAUDING)
(众人欢呼)
(ALL CHEERING)
哦，他太爱她了。
Oh, he loves her so much.
是啊。
Yeah.
约翰：专程为您准备的特别快递。
JOHN: And special delivery, just for you.
一份礼物。
A gift.
露西：白手套服务，精心呵护。
LUCY: A white glove service,
handled with care.
约翰：请在这里签名。
JOHN: If you could just sign here.
露西：在这里签缩写。
LUCY: Initial here.
约翰：非常感谢，祝您愉快。
JOHN: Thank you very much
and have a good day.
(露西轻笑)
(LUCY CHUCKLES)
总有一天，毫无缘由地...
One day, for no reason in particular...
你们会开始互相厌恶。
you two will start to hate each other.
你们会互相怨恨...
You'll resent each other...
会把对方的存在视为理所当然...
you'll take each other for granted...
你们会停止亲密...
You'll stop having sex...
却莫名其妙地...生几个孩子...
somehow... manage
to make a couple of kids...
然后你们会厌倦彼此...
and then you'll get sick of each other...
其中一方会背叛另一方...
And one of you will cheat on the other...
接着你们会争吵。
and then you'll fight.
起初不会在孩子面前，但后来...
At first, not in front
of the kids, but then...
就会当着孩子的面...
in front of the kids...
然后你们会怨恨孩子目睹争吵...
and then you resent the kids
for seeing you fight...
接着你们会申请离婚...
and then you file for divorce...
为财产分割争吵不休...
and you fight about...
为孩子的抚养权争执...
who owns what and...
直到一切...
who gets the kids when until it's...
彻底结束。
all over.
(人群欢呼鼓掌)。
(CROWD CHEERING, APPLAUDING)
约翰：为什么人们还要结婚？
JOHN: Why does anybody even get married?
露西：因为大家都说应该结婚。
LUCY: Because people tell them
they should.
也因为孤独。
And because they're lonely.
更因为怀抱希望。
And because they're hopeful.
他们想做得和父母不一样。
They want to do it differently
than their parents.
(轻柔的抒情音乐持续)。
(SOFT EMOTIONAL MUSIC CONTINUING)
- (欢快音乐响起)
- (热闹的交谈声)。
- (UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
- (LIVELY CHATTER)
(乐队演奏《仅此而已》)。
(BAND PLAYING THAT'S ALL)
女歌手：
♪ 我只能给你永恒的爱 ♪
WOMAN: ♪ I can only give you love ♪
♪ 和随叫随到的承诺 ♪
♪ That lasts forever ♪
♪ 每次你需要时我都在身旁 ♪
♪ And a promise to be near
Each time you call ♪
♪ 我唯一拥有的心 ♪
♪ And the only heart I own ♪
♪ 只为你一人跳动 ♪
♪ For you and you alone ♪
♪ 仅此而已 ♪
♪ That's all ♪
♪ 我只能给你春日里的 ♪
♪ 乡间漫步 ♪
♪ I can only give you Country walks ♪
♪ 在春暖花开时 ♪
♪ In springtime ♪
♪ 当落叶纷飞时 ♪
♪ 给你紧握的手 ♪
♪ And a hand to hold
When leaves begin to fall ♪
♪ 还有这份爱 ♪
♪ 炽热如火的光芒 ♪
♪ And a love Whose burning light ♪
♪ 将温暖冬夜寒凉 ♪
♪ Will warm the winter night ♪
♪ 仅此而已 ♪
♪ That's all ♪
♪ 我确信有些人 ♪
♪ There are those, I am sure ♪
♪ 曾对你说过 ♪
♪ That have told you ♪
♪ 愿以整个世界 ♪
♪ 换你一笑 ♪
♪ They would give you
The world for a toy ♪
♪ 而我只有这双臂膀 ♪
♪ 将你环绕 ♪
♪ All I have are these arms
To enfold you ♪
♪ 和时光永远无法 ♪
♪ 磨灭的爱意 ♪
♪ And a love time can Never destroy ♪
♪ 若你好奇我想要 ♪
♪ 什么回报 亲爱的 ♪
♪ If you're wondering what
I'm asking in return, dear ♪
♪ 你会欣慰地发现 ♪
♪ 我的要求如此简单 ♪
♪ You'll be glad to know
that my demands are small ♪
♪ 只要你说 ♪♪ 钟情于我 ♪
♪ Say it's me That you'll adore ♪
♪ 从此刻到永远 ♪
♪ For now and ever more ♪
♪ 仅此而已 ♪
♪ That's all ♪
（歌声持续）
(THAT'S ALL CONTINUING)
（叹息）
(SIGHS)
（虫鸣声）
(INSECTS CHIRPING)
约翰
John.
约翰！
John!
（叹息）
(SIGHS)
- 这是什么意思？
- 什么什么意思？
- What is this?
- What is what?
我们要复合吗？
Are we getting back together?
露西 我们是不是要复合了？
Lucy, are we getting back together?
我不知道
I don't know.
真的不知道
I really don't.
（叹息）
(SIGHS)
所以你就这样突然
出现在我家门口...
So you thought you'd just
show up at my door...
没有男朋友
not have a boyfriend,
同意上我的车吻我...
agree to get in my car, kiss me...
在试图忘记别人时和我上床...
fuck me while you try
to get over someone else...
然后再次离开我？
是这样吗？
and then leave me again? Is that it?
- 你觉得我毫无价值吗？
- 不 我没这么想。
- Do you think I'm worthless?
- No, I don't think that.
- 我是可随意丢弃的吗？
- 当然不是
- Am I disposable?
- Of course not.
你是在可怜我吗？
Do you feel bad for me?
觉得可怜的老约翰
搞不定自己的人生？
Poor old John can't figure his life out?
- 从来没有
- 那你为什么利用我？
- Never.
- Then why are you using me?
我没有
I'm not.
只是我通常都卑微到任你摆布。
I'm usually desperate enough to let you.
我对你卑躬屈膝
I'm a beggar for you.
当我看着你的脸...
When I see your face...
我看到皱纹和白发...
I see wrinkles and grey hair...
还有长得像你的孩子们。
and children that look like you.
我控制不住自己。
I can't help it.
(叹气)
(SIGHS)
但作为你的朋友...
But as your friend...
我必须告诉你这是个糟糕的主意。
I would tell you it's a bad idea
和一个37岁还在做宴会服务生。
to be with a 37-year-old cater waiter
连独立公寓都没有的人在一起。
who still has roommates.
我会说...
I would say...
你绝对不该嫁给一个。
you definitely shouldn't marry a guy
银行账户里只有2000美元。
that has $2,000 in his bank account...
却硬要留在这个消费不起的城市。
in a city he can't afford...
仅仅因为
who's only still there...
还想继续追逐演员梦的男人。
to keep trying to be a theatre actor
就因为曾经有人说他演得不错。
because someone told him
he was good at it once.
所以，我们之间算什么？
So, where does that leave us?
就这样。
Here.
在别人的婚礼上。
At someone else's wedding.
(嗤笑)
(SCOFFS)
我给不了你梦想的婚礼和婚姻。
I can't give you the wedding
or the marriage you want.
我甚至给不了你想要的恋爱关系。
I couldn't even give you
the relationship you wanted.
这么多年过去
It's been years,
我依然负担不起和你在一起的生活。
and I still can't afford to be with you.
你说得对...
You're right...
你确实负担不起。
You can't.
但负担不起
But just because you can't afford it,
不代表值得拥有。
doesn't mean it's worth having.
你并不想要我。
You don't want me.
我当然想要你。
Of course I want you.
你到底有没有在听我说话？
Are you even listening to me?
约翰，我们已经太久。
John, you and I haven't been
together properly...
没有真正在一起了。
in so long that you've forgotten.
你不想和我在一起是因为我人品不好。
You don't want to be with me
because I'm not a good person.
我尖酸刻薄...
I'm judgmental...
物质主义又冷漠无情。
and materialistic, and cold.
我和你分手就是因为你穷。
I broke up with you because you're broke.
我一次又一次地伤害你。
I've hurt you over and over.
你恨我。
You hate me.
我不恨你。
I don't hate you.
露西：你恨的。
LUCY: You do.
你恨我是对的，因为我糟糕透顶。
And you're right to hate me,
because I'm awful.
即便是现在...
Even now...
我还在盘算：如果选择嫁给你。
I'm thinking: If I choose to marry you...
余生都只能
I'm gonna be sitting across from you
和你坐在廉价的破餐馆里吃饭。
in cheap shitty restaurants
for the rest of my life.
坐着你那辆破车出行。
I'll be riding in your shitty car,
住在你简陋的卧室里。
and living in your shitty bedroom...
为25美元和你吵架。
and fighting with you about $25.
我在权衡和你在一起的代价。
I'm weighing being with you...
值不值得忍受这些糟糕的妥协。
against these shit tradeoffs.
我在做算术题。
I'm doing math.
这就是真实的我。
This is what I'm like.
我知道你是什么样的人。
I know what you're like.
露西：那你怎么还能爱我？
LUCY: Then how could you still love me?
(叹气)
(SIGHS)
(远处播放着欢快的音乐)。
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING IN DISTANCE)
(手机微弱震动)。
(PHONE VIBRATING FAINTLY)
(叹气)
(SIGHS)
(手机震动)
(PHONE VIBRATING)
- 苏菲？
- 露西。
- Sophie?
- Lucy.
我不知道还能打给谁。
I didn't know who else to call.
我还没告诉任何人。
I haven't told anyone.
我在城里没有朋友。
I don't have any friends in the city
而且我的律师都不接电话...
and my lawyers aren't picking up and...
- 发生什么事了？
- (电话里门铃嗡嗡响)。
- What's going on?
- (DOORBELL BUZZING ON PHONE)
苏菲：马克在我楼下。
SOPHIE: Mark is outside my building.
(紧张的音乐播放)。
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
我报了警但他们说不会来。
I called the cops
but they said they won't come
除非他试图闯入。
unless he's trying to break in.
- 然后...
- (电话里门铃嗡嗡响)。
- And...
- (DOORBELL BUZZING ON PHONE)
他并没有试图闯入，
he's not trying to break in,
只是在不停按门铃。
he's just buzzing the doorbell.
这已经构成骚扰了，他们应该——。
That's still harassment, they should--
约会后他坚持送我回家。
He walked me home after the date.
我不该让他这么做的，但是...
Which I shouldn't have let him do, but...
我当时很害怕...(呼气)。
I was scared and... (EXHALES)
- 都是我的错。
- 约翰：露西。
- It's my fault.
- JOHN: Lucy.
这不是你的错。
That's not your fault.
约翰：我们能先谈完吗？
JOHN: Can we finish talking, please?
苏菲：他说只想谈谈，
SOPHIE: He says he just
wants to talk about it,
但我不会让他进来的。
but I'm not gonna let him in.
- 千万别。
- (门铃持续嗡嗡响)。
- No.
- (DOORBELL CONTINUES BUZZING)
把门反锁好。
Bolt your door.
我在曼哈顿外约一小时车程，
I'm about an hour outside of Manhattan,
但我会尽快赶到。
but I'll try to get there sooner.
苏菲：我担心有人会给他。
SOPHIE: I'm worried
someone's going to open
开公寓楼的大门。
the building door for him.
露西：我快到了。
LUCY: I'm almost there.
他必须离开。他不能整晚都待在外面吧？
He has to leave. He can't stay
outside all night, can he?
我要你告诉他有人正在赶来。
I want you to tell him
someone is on their way.
(门铃嗡嗡响)
(DOORBELL BUZZES)
(门锁开启声)
(DOOR BUZZES)
苏菲，我是露西。
Sophie, it's Lucy.
苏菲：他走了吗？
SOPHIE: Is he gone?
是的。我们来时这里没人。
Yes. No one was here when we got here.
苏菲：哦。
他肯定是听到你要来。
SOPHIE: Oh. He must've run away
就逃走了。
when I said that you're coming.
我能进来吗？
Can I come in?
(门锁咔嗒声，门吱呀打开)。
(DOOR LATCH CLICKS, CREAKS OPEN)
- 嗨。
- Hi.
你还好吗？
How are you holding up?
呃，情况不妙。
（紧张地干笑，叹气）
Uh, not good. (CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY, SIGHS)
（呼气）马克听起来真的很生气。
(EXHALES) Mark sounded really angry.
（发抖）
(SHUDDERING)
他生气是因为...
Well, he's angry because...
他以为自己能侥幸逃脱...
he thought he was going
to get away with something...
但他不会得逞...
but he won't...
因为你不会让他得逞。
because you're not going to let him.
你很勇敢。
You are brave.
能抱抱你吗？
Can I hug you?
（抽泣）
(SOBS)
（哭泣）
(CRYING)
知道我在想什么吗？（吸鼻子）
You know what I've been
thinking about? (SNIFFLES)
（轻声）什么？
(WHISPERING) What?
我真的需要找个男朋友。
I really need to get a boyfriend
这样就有可以打电话的人。
so that I have someone to call
而不是我那该死的媒人。
that's not my fucking matchmaker.
（两人大笑）
(BOTH LAUGH)
我会孤独终老的。
I'm going to die alone.
（笑）
(LAUGHS)
苏菲。
Sophie.
（疲惫叹气）
(SIGHS WEARILY)
我保证，你会嫁给此生挚爱。
I promise you, you're going to
marry the love of your life.
你别指望我相信这话。
You don't expect me to believe that.
你不需要相信。
You don't have to believe it.
我相信就行。
I believe it.
苏菲：让我猜猜。
SOPHIE: Let me guess.
符合我一大堆条件的人？（干笑）
Someone who checks a lot of
my boxes? (CHUCKLES DRYLY)
我没奢求奇迹。
I'm not asking for a miracle.
我只想好好爱一个人。
I just want to love someone.
一个也会情不自禁爱我的人。
Someone who can't help but love me back.
她睡着了。
She's asleep.
很好。
Good.
你还好吗？
You okay?
嗯。
Yeah.
你该回家了。
You should go home.
我先送你回去。
I'll take you home first.
我要睡在她沙发上...
I'm gonna sleep on her couch...
等她醒了帮她申请限制令。
and help her get a restraining order
when she wakes up.
好吧。
Okay.
谢谢送我。
Thanks for the ride.
应该的。
Yeah, of course.
你问我为何能爱你。
You asked how I could love you.
就这么爱了。
I just do.
这是最简单的事。
It's the easiest thing.
我也爱你。
I love you too.
（轻笑）比你想象的更爱。
(CHUCKLES) More than you know.
你是我知道自己能爱的唯一证明。
You're the only reason I know
I'm capable of love.
我算了笔账。
I've been doing some math.
- 是吗？
- 是的。
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
我准备好向你提出一个提议了。
And I'm ready to make you an offer.
好啊。
Okay.
就是这个提议。
Here's the offer.
我现在爱你，
就像从前爱你一样...
I love you now, like I loved you before...
我会爱你直到生命尽头。
I'll love you 'til the day I die.
这是一生的承诺。
It's a lifetime guarantee.
我不会再像从前那样把它遗忘...
And I won't forget it the way I used to...
即使处境艰难也不会。
even when things are shit.
我会每天设置提醒。
I'll make a calendar item
时刻提醒自己我深爱着你。
every day reminding myself
that I love you.
我会成为你的依靠。
I'll be your certainty.
这是我的最终承诺。
It's my final offer.
你不能讨价还价
You can't negotiate because
因为我已经倾尽所有。
I don't have anything else to offer you.
成交。
Deal.
(轻柔浪漫音乐响起)。
(SOFT ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING)
老实说我不确定
Now I admit, I'm not confident
能否让自己摆脱经济困境。
that I can make myself less broke.
你不需要担心这个。
You don't need to worry about that.
你知道我能照顾好自己。
You know I can take care of myself.
嗯，我知道。
Yeah, I know.
不是为了你。
It's not for you.
是为了我自己。
It's for me.
为了我们。
For us.
你给了我勇气
You make me brave enough
让我敢于承认自己想要幸福。
to admit that I want to be happy.
想和你一起幸福。
And I want to be happy with you.
我会多接些餐饮兼职...
And I'm gonna pick up
more catering shifts...
要求加薪...
And ask for a raise...
找份正经餐厅的服务员工作...
I'll find a serving job
at an actual restaurant...
不再拒绝商业广告试镜，
And I won't say no
to commercial auditions,
虽然很烦人...
even though they're annoying...
会认真找个经纪人。
I'll make an actual effort
to find a manager.
(音乐渐强)
(MUSIC SWELLS)
我还要搬出现在公寓。
And I'm going to move out of my apartment.
把车卖掉。
And sell my car.
别卖车。
Don't sell your car.
不卖？
No?
不，我们就这样...
No, let's just...
开着它到处兜风...
Let's just drive around in it...
直到它彻底报废再也开不动为止。
until it breaks down
and it won't move anymore.
(音乐渐强)
(MUSIC SWELLS)
(鸟鸣声)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
露西：我最近总梦到。
LUCY: I've been dreaming about
最早结婚的那对恋人。
the first people who got married.
两个原始人...
在狩猎采集之余...
Two cavepeople... fell in love...
相爱了。
in between the hunting and the gathering.
在梦里...
And in my dream...
我不断追问自己...
I keep asking myself...
是什么让他们成为彼此的天作之合？
what made them perfect for each other?
经济背景相似？
Similar economic background?
政治立场一致？
Politically aligned?
外貌匹配度相当？
Well-matched in their attractiveness?
成长环境相近？
Similar upbringing?
还是说...
Or...
另有原因？
was it something else?
就像你我这样的感觉？
Something like you and me?
(浪漫音乐继续)。
(ROMANTIC MUSIC CONTINUING)
嘿，伙计。
Hey, man.
给我来份鸡肉盖饭？
Can I get two chicken over rice?
店员：好的。
MAN: Yeah.
多谢，不用找了。
Thanks a lot. Keep that.
你要走了真遗憾，薇。
I'm sad you're leaving, Vi.
薇奥莱特：我也舍不得
。伦敦分部确实需要我。
VIOLET: Me too. They really
need me at the London office.
我第一个通知你而不是其他Ador
e女孩...
And I'm calling you first
of all the Adore girls...
因为CEO问我该提拔谁。
because the CEOs asked me
who should be asked to step up
来担任纽约分部主管...
and be promoted... to New York head
我说非你莫属。
and I said it absolutely has to be you.
- 我？
- 没错。
- Me?
- Yes.
- 你要升职了。
- (露西轻声笑)。
- You're getting a promotion.
- (LUCY CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(大笑)
(LAUGHS)
薇奥莱特：有什么好笑的？
VIOLET: What's so funny?
其实我本来打算明天。
Well, I was going to hand in
提交辞职信的。
my resignation letter tomorrow.
薇奥莱特：别开玩笑了。
VIOLET: No, you weren't.
真的，连辞职信都打印好了。
Yep. I have it printed out and everything.
薇奥莱特：你不能辞职。
VIOLET: You can't quit.
辞职后打算做什么？
What would you do instead?
说实话我也不知道。
I honestly don't know.
说不定嫁个穷光蛋。
Maybe marry someone poor.
(轻声笑)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
薇奥莱特：我不明白。
VIOLET: I don't know
你在说什么。
what you're talking about.
好好考虑下吧。
Just think about it.
你还可以争取
You can negotiate
一份超高薪水。
a crazy salary, too.
想要多少薪资尽管提，
Ask for any amount you want,
我都会支持你。好吗？
and I'll support you. Okay?
好吧，我会考虑的。
Okay, I'll think about it.
薇，我得走了。我男朋友到了。
Vi, I have to go. My boyfriend's here.
薇奥莱特：等等，临走前告诉我：
VIOLET: Yeah, before you go, tell me:
昨晚苏菲·L的约会怎么样？
How did Sophie L.'s date go last night?
她挺喜欢那人的。
She liked him.
薇奥莱特：是布莱恩·A对吧？
VIOLET: Brian A., right?
对。
Yeah.
身高1米73，36岁，牙医。
5'8". 36. Dentist.
税前年收入20万美金。
200 grand before taxes.
就想找个...好姑娘。
Just... looking for a nice girl.
薇奥莱特：听起来很般配。
VIOLET: Sounds like a strong match.
(轻笑)
(CHUCKLES)
他也喜欢她。
He liked her too.
我们持谨慎乐观态度。
We are cautiously optimistic.
维奥莉特：很好。
VIOLET: Good.
你应该知道哈里·C
要去参加他的第一次约会了。
You should know Harry C.
is going on his first date.
罗丝牵了条很靠谱的红线。
Rose made a very strong match.
杰玛·N，30岁，艺术品经销商。
Gemma N., 30, an art dealer.
维，我得走了。
Vi, I have to go.
维奥莉特：行吧，
但先听听这个提议。
VIOLET: Fine, but hear the offer first.
我会的。
I will.
维奥莉特：给我打电话。
VIOLET: Call me.
嗨。
Hi.
想不想做个非常糟糕的财务决定？
How would you like to make
a very bad financial decision?
(浪漫独立音乐播放中)。
(ROMANTIC INDIE MUSIC PLAYING)
(热闹的交谈声)。
(LIVELY CHATTER)
(音乐渐弱)
(MUSIC FADES)
(广播系统模糊的公告声)。
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENT ON PA)
(浪漫民谣音乐播放中)。
(ROMANTIC FOLK MUSIC PLAYING)
(音乐渐弱)
(MUSIC FADES)